hirewriters.com 2019-04-17

# Hire Writers - Privacy Policy

**PRIVACY POLICY**

Your privacy is very important to us. We want to make your experience on the Internet as enjoyable and rewarding as possible, and we want you to use the Internet's vast array of information, tools, and opportunities with complete confidence. 

**Definitions**

We have created this Privacy Policy to demonstrate our firm commitment to privacy and security. This Privacy Policy describes how our "Company" or "Site" which for the rest of this policy, refers to HireWriters.com, collects information from all end users of our Internet services (the "Services")-those who access some of our Services but do not have accounts ("Visitors") as well as those who may purchase Products and/or services to subscribe to the Service ("Members")-what we do with the information we collect, and the choices Visitors and Members have concerning the collection and use of such information. We request that you read this Privacy Policy carefully. 

**Acceptance and Updates**

By using the Site, you agree to the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy, you are prohibited from using the Site. We reserve the right to change this Privacy Policy without prior notice. You can find out when this Privacy Policy was last revised by referring to the “Last Updated” legend at the top of this page. Any changes to our Privacy Policy will become effective upon our posting of the revised Privacy Policy on the Site. Use of the Site following such changes constitutes your acceptance of the revised Privacy Policy then in effect. 

**Information Collected by the Site**

  1. **Personal Information** is information that identifies an individual. In order for you to take advantage of particular opportunities provided through the Site (for example, to receive white papers, participate in certain forums on the Site or sign-up for the Service), we may require that you furnish Personal Information. We collect Personal Information from you, such as your name, postal address, telephone number and email address, billing information only when you voluntarily provide it to us. We may also combine Personal Information you provide to us with publicly available information, such as your organization’s name, in the event you provide us with an email address from your organization.

  2. **Non-Personal Information** is aggregated information, demographic information and any other information that does not reveal an individual’s specific identity.

  3. **Environmental Variables**. We may collect certain environmental variables, such as your MAC address, computer type, screen resolution, OS version and browser type and version. These environmental variables are collected by most websites and can be used to optimize your experience on the Site.

  4. **Cookies**. We and service providers acting on our behalf may set and access cookies on your computer. A cookie is a small text file containing a unique identification number that is transferred from a website to the hard drive of your computer so that the website administrator may identify your computer and passively track its activities on the website. This unique number identifies your web browser to our computer system. Cookies allow us to automatically remember your web browser when you use the Site. The use of cookies is an industry standard, and they are currently used on most major websites. It is possible to adjust your web browser preferences to alert you when a cookie is sent to your hard drive, or to refuse cookies altogether. While we do not require you to use cookies, certain parts of the Site will not function properly if you set your browser to refuse all cookies.

  5. **Web Beacons**. Web beacons, also known as clear GIFs or single-pixel GIFs, are small image files that we, or service providers acting on our behalf, may place in our Web pages, in our advertisements and in our emails. Working in conjunction with cookies, web beacons allow us to accurately count the number of unique users who have visited a specific Site page or section, clicked on one of our advertisements, or opened or acted upon an email. They also tell us the number of times advertisements or pages are displayed. This allows us to measure the performance of our Site, our advertising and our email campaigns.

  6. **Information That You Provide**. We may also collect Non-Personal Information, such as your interests, geographic location and website address, when you provide it to us. Unless combined with Personal Information, this information does not personally identify you. In addition, we may aggregate Personal Information in a manner such that the end product does not identify you or any other Site user. Such aggregate information is considered Non-Personal Information for purposes of this Privacy Policy.

  7. **IP Addresses**. Your Internet Protocol (IP) address is a number that is automatically assigned to the computer you are using by your Internet Service Provider (ISP), and in many cases, IP addresses are shared by multiple people. This number is identified and logged automatically in our server log files whenever you visit the Site, along with the time(s) of your visit(s) and the page(s) you visited. Collecting IP addresses is standard practice on the Internet and is done automatically by many websites.

**Personal and Non-Personal Information Possible Usage**

Introduction: Our company collects information in different ways from Visitors and Members who access the various parts of our Services and the network of Web sites accessible through our Service. 

Registration:  Members may be asked to provide certain personal information when they sign up for our Products or Services including name, email address, username, address, telephone number, billing information (such as a credit card number, although we do not store it), and the type of personal computer being used to access the Services. The personal information collected from Members during the registration process is used to manage each Member's account (such as for billing purposes). This information may be shared with third parties, as stated herein, or in special circumstances. 

However, in instances where our company and a partner jointly promote our Services, we may provide the partner certain personal information, such as the name, email address, username, address, and username of persons who subscribed to the Services as a result of the joint promotion for the purpose of offering you other products and services. 

In this instance, personal information may not be used by the partner for any other purpose. We may also generate non-identifying and aggregate profiles from personal information Members provide during registration (such as the total number, but not the names, of Members). As explained in more detail below, we may use this aggregated and non-identifying information to sell advertisements that appear on the Services. 

Also, with purchases, we supply our member's contact information, to our business partners, who then may contact the member by telephone after the member purchase. Sales proceeds are collected by the that business partner company.  We also may supply other companies with contact information, for mail offers we believe would be of interest to our members, with or without compensation from those companies.  At times we may send an advertisement for a third party product, where we collect the sales proceeds, and forward the purchaser's information to that third party. 

Our Company Partners and Sponsors:  Some products and services may be offered to Visitors and Members in conjunction with an affiliate, independent contractor seller or non-affiliated partner. To provide Visitors and Members some of these products and services, the partner may need to collect and maintain personal information. 

Online Shopping:  At some Web sites, you can purchase products and services or register to receive materials, such as a newsletter, catalog or new product and service updates. In many cases, you may be asked to provide contact information, such as your name, address, email address, phone number, and credit/debit card information. 

If you complete an order for someone else, such as an online gift order sent directly to a recipient, you may be asked to provide information about the recipient, such as the recipient's name, address, and phone number. Our company has no control over the third parties' use of any personal information you provide when placing such an order. Please exercise care when doing so. 

If you order services or products directly from our company, we use the personal information you provide to process that order.  We do share this information with outside parties that we do business with. 

Online Advertisements:  Our company may display our online advertisements. In those cases we share information about our Visitors and Members collected through the registration process as well as through online surveys and promotions with these advertisers. 

Additionally, in some instances, we use this information to deliver tailored advertisements or joint ventures. For instance, an advertiser or joint venture company tells us the audience they want to reach and provides us an advertisement tailored to the audience. Based upon the information we have collected, we may then display or send the advertisement to the intended audience. Our company does share personal information about its Visitors or Members with these advertisers or joint venture companies.

Responses to Email Inquiries: When Visitors or Members send email inquiries to our company, the return email address is used to answer the email inquiry we receive. 

Voluntary Customer Surveys:  We may periodically conduct both business and individual customer surveys. We encourage our customers to participate in these surveys because they provide us with important information that helps us to improve the types of products and services we offer and how we provide them to you. 

We may take the information we receive from individuals responding to our Customer Surveys and combine (or aggregate) it with the responses of other customers we may have, to create broader, generic responses to the survey questions (such as gender, age, residence, hobbies, education, employment, industry sector, or other demographic information). We then use the aggregated information to improve the quality of our services to you, and to develop new services and products. This aggregated, non-personally identifying information may be shared with third parties.

Promotions:  Our company may offer polls, contests, sweepstakes, drawings, games, content, or other promotions that are sponsored by or cobranded with third parties. You may be entered in a sweepstakes, contest, or other promotion, simply by making a purchase from us or by providing us with personally identifiable information for some other reason or purpose. Due to these third party relationships, the third parties may obtain personally identifiable information that visitors voluntarily submit to our company. Our company has no control over third parties' use of this information. 

Additionally, personally identifiable information may be collected when you order products, enter contests, vote in polls or otherwise express an opinion, subscribe to one of our services such as our online newsletters, or participate in one of our online forums or communities. The types of personally identifiable information that may be collected at these pages include but may not be limited to: name, address, e-mail address, telephone number, fax number, credit card information, and information about your interests in and use of various products, programs, and services. Our sponsors or third parties may send you material that relates to our company's services, products or activities.

Payment Processing:  We use a third-party when processing payments for the Site. When you use your credit card information, that information is sent directly to the secure third-party. HireWriters does not have access to your full credit card number, and does not store such inforamtion on its own systems. You acknowledge and agree that any Personal Information that you provide in connection with such credit card payments will be transmitted directly to the Payment Service. Information transmitted to the Payment Service is encrypted using SSL software. The Payment Service is required to comply with all applicable privacy and security laws and the rules and regulations issued by the credit card companies, however, HireWriters is not responsible for the Payment Service’s failure to comply with such laws, rules and/or regulations. 

Special Cases:  We may disclose personal information about Visitors or Members, or information regarding your use of the Services or Web sites accessible through our Services, for any reason if, in our sole discretion, we believe that it is reasonable to do so, including: credit agencies, collection agencies, merchant database agencies, law enforcement, or to satisfy laws, such as the Electronic Communications Privacy Act, the Child Online Privacy Act, regulations, or governmental or legal requests for such information; to disclose information that is necessary to identify, contact, or bring legal action against someone who may be violating our Acceptable Use Policy or Terms Of Service, or other user policies; to operate the Services properly; or to protect our company and our Members. 

Email Opt Out:  You may request to not receive any site updates, or marketing promotions from us via email but contacting us and asking to unsubscribe your email address, or you may do it yourself, by clicking the link at the bottom of the email you receive that says "unsubscribe". If you wish to opt out of receiving "functional emails" from us, which are emails like receiving your lost password information, email confirmations, and other emails directly related to the usage of your account at the Site, you must close your account entirely. 

Your Rights:  You have the following data protection rights: 6.1. You can request access, correction, updates or deletion of your personal information. 6.2. You can object to processing of your personal information, ask us to restrict processing of your personal information or request portability of your personal information. 6.3. If we have collected and process your personal information with your consent, then you can withdraw your consent at any time. Withdrawing your consent will not affect the lawfulness of any processing we conducted prior to your withdrawal, nor will it affect processing of your personal information conducted in reliance on lawful processing grounds other than consent. You can request to obtain a copy of your Personal Data in a commonly used electronic format so that you can manage and move it. Please note that we may ask you to verify your identity before responding to such requests. 

Retention Period:  We will retain your Personal Information for the period necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy unless a longer retention period is permitted or required by law. 

Notice of Compliance to California Residents – Your California Privacy Rights Under The California Online Privacy Protection Act and the California Business and Professions Code 

This privacy policy identifies the categories of personally identifiable information that our company collects through our Web site or online service, about individual consumers who use or visit our company's commercial Web site or online service and the categories of third-party persons or entities with whom our company may share that personally identifiable information.

Our company does not maintain a process for an individual consumer who uses or visits our commercial Web site or online service to review and request changes to any of his or her personally identifiable information that is collected through our Web site or online service.

See the section below entitled "Revisions To This Policy" for a description of the process by which our company notifies consumers who use or visit our commercial Web site or online service of material changes to our company's privacy policy for this Web site or online service.

The effective date of this privacy policy is listed at the end of this privacy policy  under the heading, "Last updated."

For the purposes of this policy and California compliance the following definitions apply:

Depending on the visitor's activity, in our commercial Web site or online service, the following "personally identifiable information" may be collected, in addition to information set forth in other sections of this document.

The term "personally identifiable information" means individually identifiable information about an individual consumer collected online by our company from an individual and maintained by our company in an accessible form, and may include any of the following:

(1) A first and last name.  
(2) A home or other physical address, including street name and name of a city or town.  
(3) An e-mail address.  
(4) A telephone number.  
(5) A social security number.  
(6) Any other identifier that permits the physical or online contacting of a specific individual.  
(7) Information concerning a user that the Web site or online service collects online, from the user, and maintains in personally identifiable form, in combination with an identifier described within this privacy policy.

Under California Law SB 27, California residents have the right to receive, once a   
year, information about third parties with whom we have shared information about you   
or your family for their marketing purposes during the previous calendar year, and a   
description of the categories of personal information shared. To make such a request,   
please send an email to [support@HireWriters.com](mailto:Privacy@PrivacyRequest.com)  and please include the phrase   
"California Privacy Request" in the subject line, the domain name of the Web site you are inquiring about, along with your name,  address and email address. We will respond to you within thirty days of receiving  such a request. 

"Cookies" and How Our Company Uses Them. A "cookie" is a small data file that can be placed on your hard drive when you visit certain Web sites. Our company may use cookies to collect, store, and sometimes track information for purposes stated herein as well as for statistical purposes to improve the products and services we provide and to manage our telecommunications networks. 

Cookies may also be shared with third party advertising networks that use this data to retarget you for ads about the Site, or other potential Sites. 

Advertisers and partners may also use their own cookies. We do not control use of these cookies and expressly disclaim responsibility for information collected through them. 

Our Company Commitment to Children's Privacy. Protecting children's privacy is especially important to us. It is our policy to comply with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 and all other applicable laws. Therefore we restrict our Web site to persons eighteen years or older.

YOU MUST BE EIGHTEEN (18) YEARS OR OLDER TO ACCESS THIS WEB SITE. IF YOU ARE UNDER EIGHTEEN YEARS OF AGE, YOU ARE NOT PERMITTED TO ACCESS THIS WEB SITE FOR ANY REASON. DUE TO THE AGE RESTRICTIONS FOR USE OF THIS WEB SITE, NO INFORMATION OBTAINED BY THIS WEB SITE, FALLS WITHIN THE CHILDREN'S ONLINE PRIVACY PROTECTION ACT (COPPA) AND IS NOT MONITORED AS DOING SO.

Public Forums:  Please remember that any information you may disclose in any Member Directory, chat, profile, interests selected, profile, content you submit to our website, or other public areas of our Web sites or the Internet,(collectively known as "Forums") becomes public information. You should exercise caution when deciding to disclose personal information in these public areas. We are not responsible for the use of any Personal Information you disclose through the Forums. 

Our Company's Commitment to Data Security:  Services and Web sites we sponsor have security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under our control. While we make every effort to ensure the integrity and security of our network and systems, we cannot guarantee that our security measures will prevent third-party "hackers" from illegally obtaining this information. 

Where to Direct Questions About Our Privacy Policy:  If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or the practices described herein, you may contact us through the contact information provided on this Web site. 

Revisions to This Policy: Our company reserves the right to revise, amend, or modify this policy, our Terms Of Service agreement, and our other policies and agreements at any time and in any manner, by updating this posting. Your use of this site after such changes are implemented constitutes your acknowledgement and acceptance of these changes. Please consult this privacy statement prior to every use for any changes.

Last updated: May 24, 2018 

Copyright © 2003-2020 InternetMarketingLawProducts.com  for **HireWriters.com.**
